healthdata.org 2014-05-24

# Privacy Policy | Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation

## Our commitment to privacy

The Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation (IHME) is committed to respecting your privacy and applying appropriate protection and management of any information you share with us. IHME provides this privacy policy to clearly explain our online information practices and how this information is collected and used. As part of the University of Washington, IHME adheres to the university’s overarching privacy policy.

## The information we collect and how we use it

There are some places on the website where we ask you to provide certain information about yourself, such as your name, email address, or mailing address. This information is collected strictly for use by IHME and will not be shared with any third parties.

In what cases we request we request private information:

  * **Subscribing to IHME updates and newsletters**
    * If you would like to receive email updates about IHME’s research, we ask that you provide a valid email address.
  * **Ordering IHME publications**
    * If you would like to receive printed copies of IHME publications, you may request a copy on our website. We ask for your mailing information so we can send you the printed materials you requested. 
  * **Applying to the Post-Bachelor Fellowship  **
    * As part of the online application process for the Post-Bachelor Fellowship, we collect personal information, as well as information about your academic career. This includes first name, middle initial, last name, phone number, address, university, GPA, area of study, race, sex, reasons for your interest in IHME, how you heard about the program, résumé, and a personal statement. This information helps us process your application and is only used by those within the Education and Training department at IHME.
  * **Requesting data from the Global Health Data Exchange (GHDx)**
    * As part of our efforts to share the data we collect around the world, we make available a number of datasets from IHME and other organizations. We used to require a user name and valid email address to access these data. As of February 2012, we no longer require this information to download data. If you previously registered, we have deleted your account information permanently from our records.

## Our commitment to data security

To prevent unauthorized access to your personal data, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have implemented commercially-reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect through this website. 

## Questions about our privacy policy

If you have any questions about IHME’s privacy policy, please contact us by email or at the following address:

Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation

2301 5th Ave., Suite 600

Seattle, WA 98121

USA

Main phone: +1-206-897-2800

Fax: +1-206-897-2899
